All right, so here we go.
First thing, I'd like to talk a little bit about the ACI courses.
And of course, that's mostly philosophy.
But to be a good meditation teacher and to be a good retreat teacher, I think
you need the philosophy also.
So we have eight, we have...
all of ACI courses are 36 courses.
I designed them to take about five weeks each,
which is two classes per week.
And I started teaching them over 25 years ago.
So I taught three courses per year.
And the first 18 courses took six years.
And we started in New York City,
in a small apartment,
in a special area of New York.
It's called Hell's Kitchen.
Very dangerous part of New York.
Many students who came, their car was stolen during the class.
But we didn't have any money.
So we rented a place there.
We start with, I think, eight students in the first class.
And we sit around the kitchen table.
There are two dogs. Maybe you heard the recording.
And in the first class, there's one strange guy.
He's a very successful stock market guy.
And he said, this is important.
This is historical.
This will change the world.
Can I make recording?
So he has little cheap cassette recordings.
And he insists to record.
And those are still available.
You can listen to them.
80% Geshe Michael, 20% dogs.
But I think it's fun.
So I did 18 courses.
They cover all the Geshe course.
So there are five main subjects in the Geshe course.
And in the 18 foundation ACI courses,
I put all the Geshe course, most of the important material.
And my dream
is that in the modern world,
family people
should be the teachers of Buddhism.
I think the time of monks teaching,
I honestly I think this time is finished.
Of course there are amazing monks who teach.
And Dalai Lama is a monk.
There are many great Geshe's teaching.
But actually in my monastery,
the number of monks is dropping every year.
The number of monks is dropping every year.
And it's like in the Catholic Church in America.
I think half of the priests are from other countries.
And I don't know if this structure is good for modern times, because the ACI teacher must help normal people with their normal life.
And the monk cannot teach the two husbands in the kitchen,
because they never had a fight with their wife.
And I think that's normal people's life.
So I love the monastery.
I still pay for all the education of the children.
And I built the school.
Over 500 kids.
And especially the groups in different countries like Singapore.
Where are you?
Jenny Wong.
Yeah, they are supporting most of them.
And her too.
So we are supporting the future of the monastery.
And I think they are the most beautiful places in the world.
But I honestly believe you can help more people.
Because people who need you are family people mostly.
And you had a fight with your husband.
Right, Barbara?
So you have more experience.
And you can teach it better.
So I believe the future of this teaching is with you.
I believe you are the teachers.
So please teach.
It's a lot of trouble.
Maybe you will get air conditioning.
But it's the happiest life you can do.
I don't know anyone who is happier than an ACI teacher.
To have students is like having kids.
It's a lot of trouble.
But when your kids grow up,
and those kids are beautiful people,
there's no happier feeling.
If your kids are really good kids,
then you feel special happiness.
So I'll tell you,
I don't think there's any happier thing than to be ACI teacher.
So I encourage you to do it.
So there are two big...
After I taught in New York,
the Geshe Course,
I call Baby Geshe Course.
And if you finish the 18 foundation courses,
you get a baby Geshe degree.
And that's all.
I was in...
Where was I?
I was in India.
Some of the monks from my monastery
came to visit my Geshe.
To visit my business talk.
And they came to my hotel room.
Two of them are finishing the last year of their Geshe.
High Geshe.
And 25 years.
And Hazo was with me.
And Orit.
So Scott's wife, Orit.
And they start to debate.
Orit.
Sorry.
Don't tell Scott.
Then they start to debate.
The two high Geshe candidates
to ACI students.
And they are debating a pretty difficult subject.
And Hazo kicked their ass.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Sorry to use bad words, but it's true.
So I think if you study the 18 courses seriously,
you can...
You understand.
Okay.
Then I did a three year retreat.
And my New York students asked me,
after the three year retreat,
will you teach us Tantra?
So this is secret Buddhism.
And there are two tantric colleges in Tibet of Tsongkhapa's lineage.
And my teacher was the assistant abbot of one of them.
And he taught us Tantra for about 25 years.
So I said, okay, I will teach you Tantra.
It will take six years.
We will do 18 courses.
And so I arranged all the scriptures
for 18 courses.
And I translated them.
And the whole thing is about 10,000 pages.
And I think it's the...
Personally, I believe it's the most organized tantric course in history.
So you have to finish the first 18 courses.
Then you can start the 18 secret courses.
The word Tantra has a bad name in the West.
There are some non-real Tantra.
And they're talking strange things.
It sounds like voodoo or something.
You become Buddha if you have sex with the teacher.
Or if you kill 30 chickens on the same day.
So even in India this word became dirty.
So I think we should use the traditional word.
Which is diamond way.
Vajrayana.
So we have 18 foundation courses.
And the 18 diamond way courses.
It was designed to take 12 years.
And some people came late.
They didn't finish the 18 foundation courses.
Can we study diamond way?
Please, please.
Then I like people to like me.
So I said, okay.
Then I'll tell you honestly.
I think about 75% of those people fail.
It's like they are building a big apartment building
with a bad foundation.
And it will fall down.
So I encourage you.
Learn the 18 courses.
Build a good foundation.
Then you can have 18 story apartment.
Vajrayana.
Diamond Way.
On top of that.
I had a walk and talk
with somebody just now.
They say,
I want to be a Buddha in this life.
That's the function of the Diamond Way courses.
Esa es la diferencia entre el camino del diamante y los cursos básicos.
Si estudias los cursos básicos
y no estudias los cursos del camino del diamante,
te convertirás en un buda,
como en diez billones de años,
o más.
Pero si estudias el segundo grupo de dieciocho cursos,
es fácil hacerlo en una vida,
antes de que mueras, y luego ya no tienes que morir.
Esa es la estructura.
Para ser honestos,
el estudio en el monasterio
es un poco caótico.
Por ejemplo, tienes que hacer el grado Geshe y el grado pre-Geshe.
Cuando hice mi examen de pre-Geshe,
alguien tocó en mi puerta.
Ven ahora.
¿Por qué?
Es tu examen de pre-Geshe en diez minutos.
Estoy como, nadie me dijo nada.
Ellos dijeron, sí, solo decidieron.
Y esto es la costumbre.
Es muy loco en el monasterio.
Si terminas el examen de pre-Geshe, esto es la costumbre. Es muy loco en el monasterio.
Si terminas el examen de pre-Geshe, esto es la costumbre.
No sabes cuándo va a ser el examen.
Todos en tu clase tienen diferentes maestros.
Este está estudiando la clase uno, este la clase dos, este la clase tres.
Y tienes que debatir con el otro pero no sabes ni qué está estudiando.
No sabés lo que haces.
No sabes ni qué está estudiando.
Then, you know I went to Princeton. They ring the bell, you go here. They ring a big bell, the whole university.
Everyone moves at the same time. So I thought if we could have some structure of the Geshe course,
and the secret course, it's so much easier to become Buddha.
So I made everything like Princeton System. You have ten classes each course.
You have homework. You have quiz. You have final exam.
If you finish, you finish. If you don't finish, you don't finish.
So it's very clear. And I like it.
So the first thing what I'd like to do today is teach you about the structure of the foundation series.
There are eighteen courses. What are the eighteen courses?
It's good if you know before you start to become ACI teacher.
When I first studied with my first Lama, we are studying Shantideva.
It's called the Guide to the Bodhisattva's Way of Life.
And I was going to all the classes in Tibetan.
And then I was traveling to New Delhi on a train.
And all these Tibetan people were there.
They are carrying cakes and things.
They are all running into one room.
A special waiting room for the train.
And I was with my friend.
Then we decided to ask the Tibetan people,
What is all this cake? Can we get some cake?
And they said, No, no. This cake is for Dalai Lama's teacher.
The senior teacher.
He's traveling on the train today.
So we go, Oh man!
Let's go buy a cake.
We will offer cake.
So we ran to the market.
We got a cake.
And we knock on the waiting room.
And we push to the front.
And there's Dalai Lama's senior teacher.
And our teacher is standing behind him.
Then we do prostration.
And we say, We are also studying Buddhism.
He's very strange.
I met him a few times after that.
He's always doing mantra.
Without a rosary.
He's like, Oh, you're studying, huh?
Yeah, yeah, we are studying.
What book are you studying?
We don't remember the name of the book.
And our teacher is there.
He's like, Shantideva.
We're like, Shantideva.
Oh, very good, very good.
Don't be like that.
Maybe you meet somebody important on the train.
They're going to say, What's the 18 courses you are teaching?
I don't know.
But I'm a teacher.
Here we go.
Each day I will introduce you to some of the 18 courses.
Just a few minutes.
We finished in the first teacher training.
We finished the first 10.
I'm going to repeat them this afternoon
because I know many of you couldn't come to the first one.
Okay, here we go.
The first course
is called Principal Teachings of Buddhism.
It's from a very famous poem by Tsongkapa.
All of Buddhism in 14 verses.
Including Tantra.
It's the greatest summary of Buddhism ever made.
My teacher's teacher is the teacher of the Dalai Lama.
The junior teacher.
My teacher's teacher
is the teacher of this Dalai Lama.
You are in a good lineage.
His teacher
wrote an explanation of this poem.
His teacher's name is Pabongka.
That's the Lam Rim we are studying.
He also gave that teaching.
Which is about a thousand pages.
But there's a two page summary of Buddhism.
That was spoken by Tsongkapa.
The first ACI course
is that whole poetry.
Two pages.
All Buddhism.
Including secret Buddhism.
In two pages.
And then I have a commentary which is about,
I don't know, 150 pages.
So that's the first...
That's ACI course number one.
If you understand it,
you understand the whole structure of Buddhism.
Buddhism is built on three ideas.
Let's take it to the kitchen.
Okay?
If you're an ACI teacher,
and there's any idea you cannot find in the kitchen,
then you're not a good teacher.
Every Buddhist idea is in the kitchen.
Okay?
So in that first course,
there's three ideas.
Okay?
Number one.
I'm tired of fighting in the kitchen.
I'm tired of all the fighting in the world.
I want to stop
all the poverty,
all the suffering,
all the trouble,
all the unhappiness,
all the conflict,
especially in the kitchen.
I'm tired of it.
I want to stop it.
Okay?
So I don't know how you translate it.
I'm tired of it, I want to stop it.
Okay?
That's the lowest kind of Buddhism.
Number two.
If I can learn how to stop it,
I can help other people to stop it.
So you can call number two is love.
Okay?
If I can learn how to stop the trouble in my kitchen,
I can help other people to stop the suffering in their kitchen.
You can call love for everyone.
What's the Sanskrit word?
Bodhichitta.
Love for everyone.
Every kitchen should be happy.
Number three.
Understand the pen.
It doesn't come from the pen.
It comes from me.
What's emptiness?
Yeah, the pen which don't come from me.
Yeah, the pen which do not come from me.
Empty.
Impossible.
She used such a nice word today.
She said impossible.
Very nice.
Okay.
That's emptiness.
Which husband is emptiness?
I didn't do anything.
Okay?
So don't think emptiness, you close your eyes, everything's black.
That's not going to make your kitchen happy.
That's not emptiness.
Emptiness means your kitchen is empty of a husband who...
I didn't do anything.
Okay?
That's emptiness.
Those three ideas.
I'm tired of fighting in the kitchen.
I wish every kitchen could be happy.
I understand what makes me unhappy come from me.
This is all of Buddhism.
That's class number one.
Okay.
Geshe-la, you have to go faster.
Second class.
Second course.
Of the eighteen foundation courses.
It's called Buddhist Refuge.
It just means protection.
For a hundred dollars,
now everybody,
where's the protection in the kitchen?
What is the wife protected in?
What is the wife protected from?
Tim, you're the Apache.
Somebody choose.
Apache choose.
No bribery, no 50%.
What's the trouble that we protect the wife from?
Where's the Buddhist protection in the kitchen?
From planting a bad seed.
Yeah, great, great.
How does she plant a bad seed?
How will she plant a bad seed if she doesn't understand the pen?
Yeah.
She will say, I'm not stupid, you're stupid.
Okay, so we protect the wife.
The pen protects the wife
from bad kids next week.
Really?
Okay, who's got the money, honey?
Okay, let's go, let's go.
Okay, vamos, vamos.
Good answer, good answer.
Now I'm going to spend five days and many hours teaching you course number two.
Buddhist refuge.
You can call it Buddhist protection.
But she taught it to you already.
She just taught you the whole course.
The pen protects the wife.
La pluma protege la esposa.
Understand?
That's protection.
Eso es protección.
And I'll tell you something very sneaky.
Les voy a decir algo medio engañoson.
Truco, truco.
Un truco, les voy a enseñar un truco.
So in DCI,
En DCI,
we teach business.
Enseñamos negocio.
We especially don't teach religion.
Especialmente no enseñamos religión.
Last month I taught in Indonesia.
El mes pasado enseñé en Indonesia.
I taught DCI in Indonesia three weeks ago.
Enseñé DCI en Indonesia hace tres semanas.
This is the largest Muslim country in the world.
Es el país musulmán más grande en el mundo.
Two hundred fifty million Muslims.
Doscientos cincuenta millones de musulmanes.
And I cannot talk about Buddhism.
I'm just talking about business.
Solo estoy hablando acerca de negocios.
And I teach the business people
how to use the pen to protect themselves.
Y les enseño a la gente de negocios
cómo usar la pluma para que se protejan.
Okay, in the Christian religion,
what's the legal line you become Christian?
¿Cuál es la línea legal en la que te conviertes cristiano?
You get baptism.
Te bautizan.
They sprinkle water on you.
Te rocían agua.
Then you're a real Christian.
Luego ya eres un verdadero cristiano.
In Buddhism, what's the baptism?
En el budismo, ¿cuál es el bautismo?
You use the pen
Usas la pluma
for protection.
para protección.
Then you're Buddhist.
Luego ya eres un budista.
Understand?
¿Entienden?
We taught 10,000 people last month.
Le enseñamos a 10,000 personas el mes pasado.
Okay?
No, just kidding, okay?
All right, so it's important.
Es importante.
Protection.
That wife is protected from more trouble.
Esa esposa está siendo protegida de más problemas.
And that's the purpose of Buddhism.
Y ese es el propósito del budismo.
Nowadays, to be honest,
Hoy en día, para ser honest,
I think if Buddha is here,
and you ask the Buddha,
Where is Buddhism?
in this world,
I think he will say DCI.
Understand?
It's not churches.
It's not temples.
It's not the red clothes.
It's protecting people
from trouble
in the kitchen.
That's Buddhism.
So, if we don't have all red clothes,
and we don't go to temple,
and you don't have an altar in your house,
I don't care.
I want you to protect people in the kitchen.
You understand?
Okay.
All right.
Number three.
Course number three.
Meditation.
And it's called applied meditation.
Practical meditation.
We teach in DCI,
we teach meditation that all business people can do.
That's all.
Your life is much easier
if you meditate a little every day.
And it doesn't have to be religious.
Just think about the pen for 15 minutes
and read it.
Okay.
Quietly.
Do you have to sit on the floor?
Why did Buddha sit on the floor?
There's no chair.
Some people say,
Geshe-la, I can't meditate.
I cannot sit on the floor.
Shut up and sit on a chair.
I use the couch.
Shut up and sit on the couch.
I inherited a dog by accident.
He always sits next to me.
He's not allowed on the couch except during meditation time.
He also loves meditation.
Okay.
If you learn meditation,
if you learn meditation,
your life is much easier.
And you cannot see a seed open in your mind.
You cannot see the picture come out
without meditation.
It's not possible.
Meditation slows down the mind.
These seeds are opening 65 per second.
And they are creating your world.
But it's too fast.
You cannot see it.
So you must learn to meditate.
If you see one seed open
to make one pen,
then you don't need these classes.
Then you don't need these classes.
That's enough.
Then you will believe where the husband comes from.
And you will have protection.
So we have to learn to meditate.
Okay, course number four.
Course number four is called
Proof of Future Lives.
Course number four is called Proof of Future Lives.
And it's a little bit sensitive subject.
In the DCI teacher training,
we actually don't allow them to talk about future life.
Because now this is a religious thing.
If you talk about future life,
then many countries of the world,
they are uncomfortable.
But if you have a Buddhism course,
you have to talk about future life.
And you have to try to prove it.
So most of you heard Buddhism has a logic.
We study logic.
How to prove the things you cannot see with your eyes.
How many years ago?
Seventy years ago.
Seven zero.
Einstein.
From Princeton.
Some of his career.
He wrote a letter to the American president.
I can make you a bomb.
It will destroy a whole city in one minute.
If you make it now,
20 million people's life you can save.
You can save.
This war will finish in two days.
I can do it.
You know?
Then the president is like,
How?
And Einstein's like,
It's here. Don't worry.
I can see it.
I understand how to do it.
Nobody did it before.
But I understand it will work.
Buddhism is the same.
Many things you cannot see with your eyes.
You have to use your third eye.
Third eye is not mystical.
I'm sorry to destroy the mysticism.
The third eye in these Buddhist paintings
is logic.
Okay?
For example,
if the dog comes in the room
and chews on this thing,
on this thing,
if the dog comes in the room, you ready?
and chews on this thing,
and if the human writes with it,
then it must be coming from your mind.
It must be.
No choice.
You used your third eye.
Just now.
I'll say it again.
If the dog look at this thing
and decide it's a chutoy,
and if the... Sorry.
And if the... Sorry.
If the human look at the same thing
and write with it,
then logically
it must be coming from you.
Okay?
Then you just used your third eye
to see
dependent origination.
We won't talk about it.
Okay?
So,
course number four,
so course number four,
how to use your third eye
to see that there exist future life.
And you must have come from another life before.
That's all.
That's course number four.
It's called proof of future life,
but it's all for proof of past lives.
It also covers subjects like it is possible
to become a person who can see future and past.
Okay, course number five.
All about karma.
How does karma work?
It's a whole five-week course about karma.
Okay, course number six is emptiness,
and we use the Diamond Cutter Sutra.
It's probably the most famous teaching about emptiness.
So course number six,
everything's about emptiness.
It's called Diamond Cutter Sutra.
Where's the emptiness in the kitchen for zero dollars?
Nobody will answer, they're on strike.
Just tell me.
We need an audience microphone later, okay?
Okay.
No, behind you.
Where's the vacuidad in the kitchen?
Yeah.
The vacuidad in the kitchen,
the emptiness in the kitchen,
is where one of the two husbands is standing.
Which one?
I didn't do anything, okay?
Yeah.
The place where he's standing,
there's emptiness.
Because he's not real.
He's impossible.
Okay, cool.
That's all.
Now you finished course six.
Okay.
Course number seven.
You finished course six.
Okay.
Course number seven,
if you're still listening,
I'm not saying the same thing.
Okay.
You're still listening,
you're still listening.
You're still listening.
Okay.
So that's all.
Now you finish.
You finish course six.
Okay.
There is a special tradition to take 64 commitments of a bodhisattva.
There are 64 bodhisattva codes.
All bodhisattvas like to do 64 things.
In that course number seven, we learn the 64, and then you make a commitment to follow
the 64.
For example, Dr. Shenmue Chunomishin Hing, Shakyaminyan, Teche Pongta, Kochukor, Chukungyamitra,
Tsamang Ananda, Lhokta, Trongsa, Trongma,
Ma Chang Tong Ni Ten, Tsog Chang Tong, Ma Tong Chong Ni.
These are the 18 main ones.
Dr. Shenmue, these are the first two.
Praise yourself and criticize other people.
These are bodhisattva vows.
There are vows like that.
Those are 64 special vows that you can learn, and if you keep them, you become a bodhisattva.
Course number eight is called Death and the Realms of Existence.
When people die, what does it feel like?
Where do you go?
Why we can't remember our past life?
Where's the place we can go?
How to go to a good place?
It's important to study.
It's called Death and the Realms of Existence.
Where you will go after you die?
What does it feel like to die?
Like that, what will happen to you?
That's course number eight.
Course number nine is called the ethical life.
Christian has ten commandments.
Buddhism has the ten good deeds.
They're almost exactly the same.
These are rules for living your life.
Not to hurt other people.
By the way, fifteen more minutes, we take a break.
All right, course number ten.
Ten, eleven, twelve.
These are...
We are studying
the book which I forgot in the railway station.
Bodhisattva's Way and Life.
It's a very, very beautiful book.
Explains how to be like a Bodhisattva.
It's so important.
It's three courses, ten, eleven, and twelve.
In course number ten,
we start the Bodhisattva's Way and Life.
Mainly three subjects.
Okay, number one.
How to prepare for meditation.
It's a very quick, ten-minute, super power, good seeds and get rid of bad seeds.
Just before meditation,
you put some good seeds in.
Then you do confession of all your bad seeds.
Then quickly meditate before you can make more bad seeds.
Okay, that's the first subject.
Second,
perfection of giving.
How to share
what you have
with other people.
You say, Geshe-la, it's not so difficult.
You just take the hundred dollars out and you give it.
No, but sharing is an art.
Sharing is an art?
Yeah, there's ways to do it.
Elegant ways.
Powerful ways.
Okay, and you study that.
Third subject.
Second perfection.
How to not hurt other people.
Don't bother other people.
Okay, this is the second of the Bodhisattva Perfections.
This is the second of the Bodhisattva Perfections.
So those are the first ten courses.
We just reviewed what the first teacher training did.
And I think that's a good place to take a pee-pee brain.
Okay, so...